#### **Cindy Chynoweth**

# **Objectives**

To bring my 14 years working full-time as a clinical software developer, QA analyst, and clinical research on diagnoses and procedures plus team leader on many projects at 3M Health Information Systems. 2 years of medical records coding and working with kids at Primary Children's Hospital to help them smile, 2 years as Release of Health Information Specialist and years of customer service experience.

#### **Education**

**Utah State University** 

**Coding Bootcamp** 

Graduate November 2022

Weber State University, Ogden, Utah

Graduated May 2000 / Associate Degree in Applied Science

Graduated most outstanding student, Health Information Technology/Medical Records, Weber State University, Class of 2000

## Skills

HTML GitHub
CSS GitLab
GitBash NodeJS
JDelphi (tools) VS Code

JavaScript Third-party APIs (jQuery, Bootstrap)

Server-side APIs, AJAX, & JSON

Moment.js Express ServersInit testing Agile methodology

Heroku MySQL

- Object-relational mapper, or ORM (Sequelize)
- Object-oriented programming (OOP)
- Model-view-controller (MVC) framework (Handlebars.js)
- Progressive web apps (PWAs)

-	Computer science	MongoDB and NoSQL
-	React	MERN

Portfolios

Commented [CC1]:

#### Certifications

Registered Health Information Technician through the American Health Information Management Association

#### **Volunteer Experience**

Salvation Army Food Bank, April 2015—August 2015 Helped the needy with food assistant

A few different convalescent centers working with the elderly

Experience

**Hawx Pest Control** 

**550 Depot Drive** 

Ogden, UT 84404

**Task Enforcer** 

5/9/2022-Present

#### 40 hours a week

- 1. Provide written and verbal communications to our customers in a manner that demonstrates our culture of caring
- 2. Take ownership of customer cases to full resolution, communicating efficiently with internal departments when needed
- 3. Continuously learn and improve product knowledge
- 4. Managing customer expectations effectively, and solving issues related to fulfillment and order inaccuracy
- 5. Perform other duties and assignments as requested

# **Focus Workforce Management**

#### 2820 Reeves Avenue

Ogden, UT 84401

**Customer Care Representative** 

3/15/2022-4/28/2022

#### 40 hours a week

Find potential employees and set-up them up with an interview. Process them in the database with all the required information. Run background checks, clear them for employment in the United States and run a drug screening test. Give new employees their work schedule, and work attire, and place them with their assigned supervisor and department. Assist all employees with issues that come up and take care of them.

#### **Rotech Healthcare**

1821 W 4000 S

Roy, UT 84067

### **Customer Service Consultant**

1/2019 - 03/2019

#### 40 to 45 hours a week

Provide support to the customers of the Support Center (patients, referral sources, and employees) by performing tasks related to patient care and third-party reimbursement. Primarily responsible for new order intake to encompass accuracy with clinical, billing, and care-related information and processing. The first line of contact with new customers.

- Adheres to and implements all company policies and procedures, including but not limited to Clinical Programs
- 2. Brings ideas for process or efficiency improvements to the supervisor
- 3. Builds relationships with locations, field management, patients, and referral sources
- 4. Certain functions require outbound calling and data entry
- 5. Collects co-pays and deductible amounts
- 6. Complies with applicable laws and regulations
- 7. Conducts insurance verification and eligibility for services/products
- Conducts patient satisfaction calls and acts as a patient advocate to resolve questions or concerns

- Develops and maintains a working knowledge of current Medicare, Medicaid, insurance regulations, and FDA/DOT and JCAHO guidelines
- 10. Develops and maintains working knowledge of current products and services offered by the company and all applicable governmental regulations
- 11. Enhances organization's reputation by accepting ownership of duties and promoting a caring and supportive environment consistent with our mission
- 12. Maintains accuracy and quality control throughout patient contact and data input
- 13. Manages all aspects of initial intake: answering the phone and receiving faxes, collecting patient and referral source information, inputting data into IMBS and eIntake, printing tickets, assembling charts, and processing paperwork
- 14. Obtains authorization and qualification documentation
- 15. Performs other duties as required or assigned
- 16. Practices safe work habits, ensuring a safe work environment
- 17. Prepares complete and accurate files for Billing Department
- 18. Processes new orders, respond to questions, resolves issues, or forward to appropriate personnel promptly to ensure patient, referral, and employee satisfaction
- Processes work orders to field locations and coordinates timely fulfillment of products and services ordered
- Provides education to referral sources, patients, and employees on qualifications for service and 3rd party billing
- 21. Provides product/service information by answering questions and offering assistance's
- 22. Provides technical assistance to customers as required
- 23. Provides thorough review and Quality Assurance for medical necessity and documentation requirements of payors and regulatory bodies
- 24. Works extensively with elntake proprietary system

Teleperformance/ AT&T

2261 Grant Avenue

Ogden, UT 84401

**Customer Service Representative** 

02/2018 - 10/2018

### 40 hours a week

- 1. Responsible for all customer inquiries
- 2. Provide excellent customer service
- 3. Solve to resolve issues on the first call
- 4. Troubleshoot as necessary

FedEx Office

4832 S Highland Drive

Salt Lake City, UT 84117

**Customer Consultant** 

11/2016 - 02/2017

### 40 hours a week

- Demonstrated consultative behaviors in a retail environment to understand each customer's individualized needs.
- 2. Provided customer expertise in printing, signs, graphics, and shipping product lines and recommend appropriate FedEx Office products and services.
- 3. Provided an outstanding customer service experience by using consultative skills to anticipate customer needs, suggest alternatives and find solutions to meet customer needs.
- 4. Ensured all customer problems were resolved quickly and to the satisfaction of the customer.
- 5. Took complex orders using the order system and provided accurate pricing information.
- 6. Assembled parcels and prepares goods for shipping by wrapping items in insulation, inserting items in shipping containers, weighing packages, and affixing labels to parcels.
- 7. Set up and operated printing, binding, and other related equipment using other customersupplied original media and documents.

Fresh Market

2255 E 2100 S

Salt Lake City, Utah 84109

Cashier

07/2016 - 08/2016

## 32 hours a week

- 1. Greet customers and ring up their purchases with a positive and friendly attitude.
- 2. Direct and help customers with the products they are looking for.
- 3. Handle money and close out registers at the end of each shift.

3M Health Information Systems 575 W Murray Blvd. Murray, Utah 84123

#### **Clinical Development Analyst/Software Developer**

08/2001 - 05/2015

40 to 55 hours a week

- Helped Develop and maintain knowledge bases for Codefinder™, an expert system used for deriving appropriate codes from the following classification systems: ICD-9-CM, ICD-10-CM, and ICD-10-PCS. Served as a lead and member of several team projects for clients of 3M Health Information Systems. Promoted excellent customer relations by providing timely and accurate answers to coding and other expert software questions.
- 2. Did research and investigation on highly technical issues of the classification systems. Wrote rules in the knowledge bases to produce correct results from user inputs. Made revisions to the knowledge bases as required by fiscal year revisions of policies, official regulations, guidelines, and customer requirements. Participated in quality assure efforts including code reviews, and testing of the expert system and knowledge base

### **Primary Children's Medical Center**

100 N. - Mario Capecchi Drive Salt Lake City, Utah 84113

**Medical Record Coding Specialist** 

12/1999 - 08/2001

40 to 45 hours a week

- CPT-4 procedure codes, and APC assignment for outpatient encounters. Assign ICD-9-CM/ICD-10-CM diagnosis and procedure codes and DRG assignments for inpatient encounters.
- 2. Ability to code inpatient, outpatient, same-day surgery, and emergency department medical records.
- 3. Played with the kids as well and helped them smile

**South Ogden Center for Family Medicine** 

5740 Crestwood Drive Ogden, UT 84405

Medical Record Department File Clerk and Release of Medical Information Specialist

07/1998 – 12/1999

32 hours a week

- 1. Release of information from patient medical records; know the laws and regulations to do this properly.
- 2. Requesting medical records from other healthcare facilities to help the doctors and medical staff in the ongoing treatment of patients.
- 3. Make sure the doctors have signed all medical documentation that is placed in the patient medical records.
- 4. Filing loose filing; laboratory reports, x-rays, dictation, consults, and records from other doctors into the patient medical record.
- 5. Answer patient questions concerning their medical records.